[♪ opening theme song playing]
[TETIA] Wow!
You're so fast, Coco!
[laughter]
Very fast, indeed!
Agott was speeding along
as well.
Now I know why!
It was thanks to the shoes
you prepared for her!
[screeches]
What was that?
What's going on?
What did I do to Agott?
It's fine, really.
She is wearing them, isn't she?
I would take that to mean
she likes your spell.
[Coco gasps]
Straight lines
are your specialty, yes?
Perhaps there are other places
they'll come in handy.
Uh, Master Qifrey?
She's not listening.
[QIFREY] Uh?
[COCO] I had a smart thought
like Agott!
[TETIA] Uh... Master Qifrey?
Is anything the matter?
Possibly. This is Alaira's hat.
[both gasp]
[QIFREY] Hats are very important
to witches.
- We don't let them go unless...
- [all gasp]
[QIFREY] A golem?
A forbidden spell this ancient
shouldn't still be active!
It's them.
The Brimmed Caps did this!
- [Qifrey grunts]
- [BOTH] Master Qifrey!
[girls screaming]
FORBIDDEN MAGIC
[panting]
[EUINI]
So, we're running away, but...
Where to?
[panting]
That was a Brimmed Cap!
No, we can't do this!
We, uh...
[Euini whimpers]
[Euini grunts]
[SASARAN] Well,
isn't this interesting?
You actually managed
to hide from me.
[laughs]
Lucky for me,
I adore hide-and-seek.
Ready or not, here I come!
[myrphons squeak]
[EUINI] Huh?
[Richeh gasps]
[Euini gasps softly]
That's right.
My cloak no longer...
- [myrphons screaming]
- [RICHEH] Quiet!
[myrphons continue screaming]
[SASARAN] Who hides
away in darkness?
The sinner, enshrouding their
nasty little secrets.
The weakling scurrying in fear
for their safety.
And the hunter,
lying in wait for their prey.
Question is...
Which one are you?
- [RICHEH] It's gone!
- [AGOTT] It vanished!
[SASARAN] You can rule out
the latter category
because the only hunter here
is me.
[wind howling]
- [Euini gasps]
- [BOTH] Euini!
[Euini whimpers]
Please, help me!
- Close your eyes, now!
- Richeh!
- [EUINI] Ah!
- [AGOTT] Euini!
You can stand, can't you?
Come on Richeh, let's go!
Have fun blathering
at a dust cloud!
[panting]
[AGOTT] The magic affecting
the cave makes it impossible
for us to fly away.
And stretching out the stones
will only take us so far.
This isn't a foe we can escape
through cleverness or trickery.
If even Alaira
was no match for them,
what can I possibly be
expected to do? [gasps]
[gasps] Of course!
[EUINI] What is it?
[AGOTT] When Alaira crossed
the gap in the road,
she froze the air under her feet
and skated forward.
- What if we freeze...
- [RICHEH] There.
...the road itself?
Then the gaps in the seals
won't be a problem!
[pen scratching]
[AGOTT]
That should about do it.
We can slide
faster than we can run!
Well done, Richeh,
now let's be off!
- Come on! Hurry up! Go!
- [EUINI] Uh?
♪
[Euini yelping]
[EUINI] Agott,
why do your Sylph Shoes
have such incredible speed?
[AGOTT]
I'd rather not discuss it!
We need to freeze
the path ahead, and quickly!
[EUINI] Right! Allow me!
[Euini gasps softly]
At this rate,
he's going to catch up.
Use a wind spell,
we'll move faster!
[RICHEH] I...
I can't.
I don't know that many
different spells.
Just my own.
[EUINI] Oh, well...
[RICHEH] Huh?
Here. You can use my spells.
It's embarrassing,
but I'm glad I wrote them out.
If they can be of help to you.
♪
[AGOTT] This was my big chance
to take the test.
So why did I have
to get dragged into this?
[TETIA] Why did I have
to get dragged into...
[AGOTT] The day
that dragon was after us,
Tetia asked the same question.
Calamities of this magnitude
don't befall
ordinary apprentices.
It's clear the Brimmed Caps
are after something special.
And it isn't us.
[EUINI] Agott?
[AGOTT] You won't find
who you're looking for!
She's not here!
She's gone.
Taken away from us
by the Knights Moralis.
They erased her memories,
and returned her to her village!
Therefore, to pursue us further
is pointless!
Because the Outsider
whom you seek
no longer resides
within our atelier!
[Agott grunts]
[SASARAN] A declaration
worthy of an apprentice
to those foremost of liars,
the Pointed Caps.
You've learned well
the art of deception.
- [RICHEH] Agott!
- [Richeh and Euini panting]
- Agott?
- [EUINI] Agott!
[SASARAN] Poor dear.
The Pointed Caps
of the past were nasty sinners.
of the present are weaklings
who fear their own power.
Their weakness stifles you.
Binds you to the tyranny
of their rules,
your vast potential unrealized.
[AGOTT]
Smells like Conjuring Ink.
[SASARAN] The salvation
you must dream of
may be found in forbidden magic.
You could grow up this instant,
if you wished it so.
Or you could remain
forever a child.
You could become
your ideal self,
with no need to hide your magic
from the eyes of others.
Even without your shoes...
- [Agott whimpers]
- [SASARAN]...you could soar.
You could go
wherever you wanted!
As you might have noticed,
I've liberated myself
from the shackles of flesh!
There will come a day
when the world remembers
what kind of hat
witches were meant to wear.
That day is inevitable,
I assure you.
We simply seek
to hasten its arrival.
And to that end,
- there must be sacrifice.
- [Agott grunts]
Agott!
[SASARAN] If she learns
the friend who lied to save her
has fallen to harm,
and the means to undo
the damage lie within reach,
with so much to be lost,
could she turn down
the miracle our magic offers?
Children are loath
to face life's tests,
but such is how
they learn and grow.
In this case, I've devised
a little test for her.
And you, child,
will learn an excellent...
painful lesson.
[Agott yells]
[EASTHIES] In some cases,
the Brimmed Caps
tattoo their bodies
with grotesque seals.
[Agott gasps]
Are you...
No! You mustn't!
I can't let everything I have
be taken away from me!
I still need to prove
myself to... [breathes shakily]
[RICHEH] Agott!
When you fall, grab this!
When I fall?
[Agott grunts]
[Richeh grunts]
[Agott gasps]
[thudding]
What just happened to the ice?
[RICHEH] Euini broke it
from under that witch's feet.
If you leave the path,
you get caught
in the labyrinth, right?
So in theory,
the same thing should happen
if the path leaves you.
Good idea.
But hasn't that Brimmed Cap
been flying around here
all along?
[EUINI] Looks like
Agott's safe and sound.
What a relief that it worked!
To think covering up
for my own weaknesses
could lead to something useful.
I'm so happy.
Maybe I'm not so hopeless
after all!
Stop and listen to me, Master!
I...
I'm not as hopeless
as I thought I was!
as you've always told me I was!
Perhaps being unable
to do the things
that others can
is actually an opportunity
to discover the things
I can do that others can't!
[SASARAN] Very well said!
[Euini yells, grunts]
[SASARAN] And perhaps
if you'd made
better use of your abilities
and remained hidden,
I would have been willing
to leave you be.
[EUINI] Help me...
[SASARAN] Being cloaked
in shadow suggests a dark side.
A quality
you're sorely lacking.
Oh, here's an idea:
I'll grant you a new form
you'll be desperate to hide.
[RICHEH] Flying all along?
That shouldn't be possible.
Supposedly,
if something's not making
direct contact with the road,
then it should be
affected by the ancient spell
of the Romonons.
But if that doesn't apply
to the Brimmed Caps,
we're still in danger!
Let's find Euini.
We need to get back
to Master Qifrey fast.
- [AGOTT] Euini!
- [RICHEH] Euini!
[AGOTT] Euini!
- [Agott gasps]
- Euini?
[rustling]
[Euini muttering indistinctly]
[Euini groaning]
[rustling]
[Richeh gasps softly]
[Euini groaning]
[Richeh gasps]
[Euini grunting]
Agott...
Richeh, please, help me.
[grunting]
[Euini growling]
[both gasp]
[Euini huffing]
[Euini growling]
[Richeh gasps]
No... Euini!
[gasps] Richeh!
We have to do something!
We have to help Euini!
[SASARAN] Hmm.
[SASARAN]
Isn't that fascinating?
To think the scalewolf fur
from his cloak
would integrate with the spell.
You monster.
[SASARAN] You must understand,
information on forbidden spells
has grown scarce over time.
[chuckles]
We oft don't know
what they'll do
until we cast them.
Not the result I was expecting,
but I suppose it worked out
proper good that, eh?
I've heard enough out of you!
Turn Euini back to normal!
[SASARAN] If it is your wish
to save the boy, by all means,
I invite you to do so!
Magic has the power
to grant all our wishes.
What happens next is up to you.
Where are you going, Richeh?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm saving Euini.
Because...
as much as I hate doing things
I don't want to,
I hate abandoning friends
even more!
You agree, don't you?
Yes, of course I do.
But what about the myrphons?
They're scared,
and we're responsible for them.
I know it's no time for tests,
but we should at least
get them back to their flock.
And someone has to report back
about what's happened here.
To Alaira, and to Euini.
Why don't we split up?
I'll go after Euini.
You get the myrphons
safely to the exit.
[RICHEH]
I want to go after Euini!
Why are you the one
who gets to decide?
[AGOTT] I know more spells
than you do, Richeh.
I'm more prepared.
The spells at your disposal
are limited
to those you have
an interest in.
You can't be flexible
in unexpected circumstances.
Sorry if this sounds harsh,
but it's true.
As you are,
you can't help Euini.
[Richeh inhales]
[Richeh sighs]
[wind howling]
[brushbuddy squeaking]
[brushbuddy sighs]
[BRUSHBUDDY] Mm?
[brushbuddy squeaking]
Brushbuddy?
[Coco gasps softly]
♪
[COCO] Uh?
[COCO]
What happened back there?
The serpent gate attacked us.
The ground caved in.
And then,
Master Qifrey protected me.
Master Qifrey?
Tetia?
[Coco gasps softly]
[Coco breathes shakily]
Is he all right?
His glasses are broken.
And he's bleeding.
[Coco gasps]
Uh... sorry about that.
- Your glasses were cracked.
- [Tetia groans softly]
- [COCO] I wanted to make sure--
- Hush. Listen.
[distant clattering]
[QIFREY] Something's out there.
[FEMALE ROMONON]
There are witches...
Witches among us.
[MALE ROMONON]
Witches gave us these forms.
Vile, contemptible witches.
Um, Master, could they be...
Yes. Romonon citizens,
living on still
as golden statues.
[Qifrey grunts]
[BOTH] Master!
[Qifrey groans]
[COCO] You're badly hurt.
[gasps] We're in trouble here.
Their resentment towards
witches is deeply held.
[winces]
Therefore, we should assume
they'll attack us,
given the opportunity.
You need to stay
right where you are.
They won't be able
to sense your presence.
As for my cloak,
its spell appears to be ruined.
You got injured
trying to protect us.
[Coco gasps]
[QIFREY] I did.
And I will...
because I'm your master.
- Hear me.
- [BOTH] Huh?
[QIFREY] Both of you.
Stay close to me.
Very close.
[wind blows]
♪
[♪ closing theme song playing]